Welcome to “Introduction to Project Management.”
Are you interested in learning about project
management?
Do you want to learn more about what project
managers do and how to become one?
Maybe you’re just starting and not sure
what project management is or even what counts
as a project.
If you’re curious about project management,
the responsibilities of a project manager,
the skills required to become one, and careers
in project management, then this course is
for you.
Project management refers to the tools and
methodologies used to plan and execute projects.
Projects can be anything from the development
of an app to the construction of a bridge.
The important thing is that projects involve
tasks that must be accomplished to achieve
a goal and produce some value.
Nowadays, project management is a more valuable
skill than ever.
We live in a project-based economy, in which
projects are the most common method of dividing
work and producing value.
Having project management skills makes you
an attractive candidate for many jobs.
Project manager roles are expected to only
grow over the next ten years.
This course is divided into four modules.
First, you’ll learn the very basics of project
management, like what project management is.
In the second, you’ll learn about the role
played by project managers in the workplace,
different project management methodologies,
and current trends in project management.
Next, the course will cover the skills and
responsibilities expected of a project manager.
The final module will describe different career
opportunities in project management, so you
will be prepared to progress in your project
management career after finishing this course.
This course uses various teaching methods,
including videos, readings, activities, quizzes,
a final project, and interviews with project
management experts.
Let’s briefly hear these experts introduce
themselves.
You will hear more from them as the course
progresses.
Hi, I'm Greg Kuya.
I'm a project manager with over 20 years of
experience and I'm currently working on my
own project called Planet Earth Things.
We make Social Impact games.
Hello, my name is Kathern Brooks.
I'm a senior project manager at Zscaler.
Hi, my name is Erica Maldonado, and I'm a
program manager at Coursera.
Hi, I'm Kasie and I currently work as a business
consultant as well as a subject matter expert
doing course development.
In the past, I've worked as a business consultant
doing project management and program management
for large companies
as well as helping companies
do agile transformations
where they move from a
waterfall project management
methodology to an agile methodology.
Hello everyone!
My name is Daniel Yeomans.
I'm currently a subject matter expert working
with Skill Up Technologies.
However, I'm also a professor.
I work for about four different universities
in the greater Seattle area.
I do continuing education, I do corporate
training, and in addition, I also perform
course development.
Once you have completed this course, you will
receive a badge and certificate that can be
shared with prospective employers to demonstrate
your knowledge of project management.
Get ready for the next step in your project
management journey, and good luck!